quiz = [
    {
        "question": "1. What is the output of print(2 ** 3)?",
        "options": ["A. 6", "B. 8", "C. 9", "D. 5"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Which of the following is used to define a function in Python?",
        "options": ["A. def", "B. func", "C. function", "D. define"],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is the data type of: x = [1, 2, 3]?",
        "options": ["A. Dictionary", "B. Tuple", "C. List", "D. Set"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Which of the following is not a valid Python data type?",
        "options": ["A. set", "B. list", "C. map", "D. tuple"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What will print(type(\"10\")) output?",
        "options": ["A. <class 'int'>", "B. <class 'str'>", "C. <class 'float'>", "D. <class 'bool'>"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. How do you insert COMMENTS in Python code?",
        "options": ["A. // comment", "B. <!-- comment -->", "C. # comment", "D. * comment *"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is the output of print(5 // 2)?",
        "options": ["A. 2.5", "B. 2", "C. 3", "D. 2.0"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Which keyword is used to create a class in Python?",
        "options": ["A. define", "B. function", "C. class", "D. object"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What will be the output of: bool([])?",
        "options": ["A. True", "B. False", "C. None", "D. Error"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Which of the following is the correct way to open a file for reading?",
        "options": ["A. open(\"file.txt\", \"read\")", "B. open(\"file.txt\", \"r\")", "C. read(\"file.txt\")", "D. file.open(\"file.txt\")"],
        "answer": "B"
    }
]
